Papish, Nancy; Papers apap144
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Subject Files, 1968-1994; Undated; 4; 2.6 cubic ft.
  - What Works: Local Solutions to Toxic Pollution (Environmental Exchange), 1993 (Box 8 (4-Subject Files), Folder 4)
- Publications, 1966-1991; Undated; 5; 0.8 cubic ft.
  In this series there are many single-issue publications on assorted environmental topics and some historical conservation subjects. Publications related directly to Clearwater and James Bay are found in Series 1 and Series 2, respectively. Oversized publications can be found in Series 8.
  - Albany City News, 1981 October; 1982 January (Box 1 (5-Publications), Folder 1)
  - Albany Report, 1984 April (Box 1 (5-Publications), Folder 2)
  - Bird Watchers Digest, 1985 July-1985 August (Box 1 (5-Publications), Folder 3)
  - The Catskills, 1973 Spring (Box 1 (5-Publications), Folder 4)
  - "The Cloud Splitter": Albany Chapter of the Adirondack Mountain Club, 1966 March-1966 April (Box 1 (5-Publications), Folder 5)
  - Coastlines, 1977 September-1978 April (Box 1 (5-Publications), Folder 6)
  - Columbia 5th Anniversary Issue: The Hudson River, 1983 (Box 1 (5-Publications), Folder 7)
  - Communicator: Journal of NYS Outdoor Education Association, 1977 Fall-Winter (Box 1 (5-Publications), Folder 8)
  - Conservationist, 1978 March-1978 April; 1978 July-1978 August; 1978 September-1978 October (Box 1 (5-Publications), Folder 9)
  - Dutchess County Travel Guide, 1986 (Box 1 (5-Publications), Folder 10)
  - Electromagnetic Fields: Training Workbook for Working People, Undated (Box 1 (5-Publications), Folder 11)
  - EPA Journal: Decade of the Environment, 1980 November-1980 December (Box 1 (5-Publications), Folder 12)
  - Future of the Adirondack Park, Vol. I, 1971 (Box 1 (5-Publications), Folder 13)
  - Hudson River Landings, Paul Wilstach, Photocopied Excerpt, 1969 (Box 1 (5-Publications), Folder 14)
  - "The Hudson: That River's Alive"National Geographic, 1978 (Box 1 (5-Publications), Folder 15)
  - Historic Preservation, 1985 December (Box 1 (5-Publications), Folder 16)
  - Hudson River Fisherman, 1982 Autumn (Box 1 (5-Publications), Folder 17)
  - Hudson River Quarterly, 1977 December; 1979 December (Box 1 (5-Publications), Folder 18)
  - Hudson Valley Green Times, 1982 Harvest; 1983 Holiday; 1990 Holiday (Box 1 (5-Publications), Folder 19)
  - Hudson Valley, 1985 September (Box 1 (5-Publications), Folder 20)
  - Jim Morris Environmental T-Shirt Catalog, 1984 (Box 2 (5-Publications), Folder 1)
  - Kite: A Publication for the Arts, 1979 May-1979 August (Box 2 (5-Publications), Folder 2)
  - Mid-Lakes Running Lights, 1982 Summer (Box 2 (5-Publications), Folder 3)
  - National Geographic, 1983 February (Box 2 (5-Publications), Folder 4)
  - New Leaf: Center for Local Food and Agriculture, 1985 (Box 2 (5-Publications), Folder 5)
  - New York Environmental News (NYEN), 1979 May-1985 December (Box 2 (5-Publications), Folder 6)
  - New York State ERDA Review, 1981 Fall (Box 2 (5-Publications), Folder 7)
  - New York Teacher, 1991 June 24 (Box 2 (5-Publications), Folder 8)
  - "New York: The State of Art", New York State Museum, 1977 (Box 2 (5-Publications), Folder 9)
  - NYPIRG Agenda, 1991 (Box 2 (5-Publications), Folder 10)
  - Poughkeepsie Bicentennial Forum, 1976 Summer (Box 2 (5-Publications), Folder 11)
  - River: The Journal of the Hudson River Fishermen, 1985 Summer (Box 2 (5-Publications), Folder 12)
  - The River Rag, 1987-1990 (Box 2 (5-Publications), Folder 13)
  - Scenic Hudson News, 1977 Autumn (Box 2 (5-Publications), Folder 14)
  - Ski Chatter: Schenectady Winter Sports Club Newsletter, 1989 (Box 2 (5-Publications), Folder 15)
  - Trailwalker, 1976 March-1976 April (Box 2 (5-Publications), Folder 16)
  - Upriver/Downriver, 1991 March-1991 April; 1991 September-1991 October (Box 2 (5-Publications), Folder 17)
  - Village Voice Nuclear Power Article, 1991 (Box 2 (5-Publications), Folder 18)
- Photographs and Audiovisual Materials, 1978; 1984; 1989; 1993; Undated; 6; 0.2 cubic ft.
  This series contains photographs, a slide show with accompanying Cassette, a videocassette, and an Cassette.
  There are 24 photographs or postcards, most housed in sleeves and many of which are unidentified. Some of the photos depict James Bay activists, as well as what is probably a model of the Odeyak. Others depict several brick buildings. Two photographs depict what appears to be a group of high school age students. One photograph, depicting two Native hunters standing with a kill, was used as a postcard. There is a message on the back from Gretchen McHugh to Nancy Papish, dated May 7, 1991. Also included are several postcards featuring various old sloops, one color photo of the Hudson River Dayline, two identical 5 × 7 B & W photos of the Clearwater on the river, an 8 × 10 B & W photo of the Clearwater at sea, and one 8 × 10 color photo of the sloop from 1984. The latter was originally housed in an acrylic picture frame, but the archivist removed and sleeved it for preservation purposes.
  NRFC produced the slide show, titled "This Is Clearwater", in 1978. The show consists of eighty slides. There are also several additional slides which were probably not a part of this show. It is possible that some of them were a part of another NRFC slide show titled "Transportation Along the Hudson", but little information about this show is available. The slides are accompanied by an audiotape with narration by Nancy Papish and two typewritten copies of the narration script. The audiotape is approximately 26 minutes long. The slide show serves as an introduction to both Clearwater and North River Friends of Clearwater.
  The videocassette contains a documentary titled "Hudson River Chronicle: Room at the Top". The documentary was produced by WMHT Educational Telecommunications in 1989. It includes a lengthy segment on Clearwater, including footage of educational activities on the sloop. Other topics covered are river geography and history; canoeing, rafting, and fishing; PCB contamination of the river; the Hudson's role in New York's canal system; the Hudson River School of painting; and protests of a home port for nuclear missiles in New York Harbor. Running time is approximately 90 minutes.
  The Cassette contains "Capitol Connection" #9351, originally aired on Northeast Public Radio WAMC on December 22, 1993. "Capitol Connection" was a weekly radio program in which moderator Alan Chartock presented New York State Governor Mario Cuomo with questions from WAMC listeners. Near the start of the program is a brief discussion of Hydro-Quebec and James Bay. Running time is 25 minutes, 26 seconds.
  Arranged by format.
  - Assorted slides, 1981; 1986; Undated; 10 items (Box 1 (6-Photographs and Audiovisual Materials), Folder 1)
  - Photographs and Postcards, 1984; 1992; Undated; 24 items (Box 1 (6-Photographs and Audiovisual Materials), Folder 2)
  - "This Is the Clearwater", Slide Show, North River Friends of Clearwater, 1978 (Box 1 (6-Photographs and Audiovisual Materials), Folder 3)
  - "This Is the Clearwater", Slide Show Overview and Scripts, 1978 (Box 1 (6-Photographs and Audiovisual Materials), Folder 4)
  - "Capitol Connection" #9351, Northeast Public Radio WAMC, 1993 (Box 1 (6-Photographs and Audiovisual Materials), Cassette 1)
  - "Hudson River Chronicle: Room at the Top". WMHT Educational Telecommunications, 1989 (Box 1 (6-Photographs and Audiovisual Materials), Vhs 1)
- Memorabilia, Undated; 7; 0.8 cubic ft.
  This series is a mix of James Bay items and sloop materials. The James Bay memorabilia includes two T-shirts printed with a bird logo and the phrase "We Don't Have to Lose James Bay". A third T-shirt is printed with "Je Me Souviens... de la Riviere Grande Baleine. Sauvons la Riviere Grande Baleine". There is a bumper sticker of the same design as the "Je Me Souviens?" James Bay T-shirt.
  Sloop materials include two copies of Clearwater's "Litterbag Songbook", a plastic shopping bag printed with lyrics for several traditional songs. There are two complete T-shirts with images of the Clearwater; one has the name of the sloop on it while the the other reads "North River Friends of Clearwater". There is also a collection of T-shirt fronts, cut out of the original garments so that just the decoration on the front was saved. The series also features a dozen Clearwater buttons and several canvas banners used at sails and fundraisers. About half a dozen banners and posters were rolled into map tubes for preservation and can be found in the oversize series.
  - "Je Me Souviens de la Riviere Grande Baleine", T-shirt, Undated (Box 1 (7-Memorabilia), Folder 1)
  - "We Don't Have to Lose James Bay", T-shirts, Undated (Box 1 (7-Memorabilia), Folder 2)
  - Litterbag Songbook, Undated (Box 1 (7-Memorabilia), Folder 3)
  - "Je Me Souviens de la Riviere Grande Baleine", Bumper Sticker, Undated (Box 1 (7-Memorabilia), Folder 4)
  - Sample T-Shirt Screen Prints on Cotton, Two Whole T-Shirts, Various Sayings and Images, Undated (Box 2 (7-Memorabilia), Folder 1)
  - Canvas Banner: Rummage Sale, Undated (Box 2 (7-Memorabilia), Folder 2)
  - Canvas Banner: Sloop Festival, Undated (Box 2 (7-Memorabilia), Folder 3)
  - Dozen Blue Buttons with Sloop Silhouette, All Say "Clearwater", Undated (Box 2 (7-Memorabilia), Folder 4)
- Oversized Materials - Posters, Displays, and Advertisements, 1973-1975; 1978-1979; 1990-1993; Undated; 8; 1.5 cubic ft.
  This series consists of oversized posters, maps, and tabloid-size publications, most of which relate to either Clearwater or James Bay. Four items that arrived at the archives tightly rolled are housed in map tubes; two banners are rolled around the outside of map tubes and housed in archival-quality muslin bags.
  In addition, fifteen large posterboard displays used as promotional tools by NRFC originally accompanied Nancy Papish's papers. For preservation reasons, most of these displays were disassembled. Items from the displays were placed in folders, along with photographs of the original exhibits. Since most of the displays were untitled, the archivist added numbers to identify each one. The box for this series contains a folder for each display that was disassembled. All items that could be removed from the displays were placed in the appropriate folders. Some displays were missing items that had once been attached. It is likely that these items were removed by NRFC for use in other displays. Displays with items missing are marked as incomplete in the. Display 12 included a large New York State map that was glued to the posterboard; this was kept intact.
  Arranged alphabetically and by format.
  - "Acting in All Our Interests to Harvest Wood in a Greener World", Poster, Meyer International Forest Products, 1990 (Oversized 1, Folder 1)
  - "Amazon North: Assault on James Bay", Earthroots, 1991 (Oversized 1, Folder 2)
  - Benefit Concert for Clearwater -- Poster, April 19 written, Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 3)
  - "Bicentennial Celebration: View and Condensed History of the City of Albany", ca. 1886 (Oversized 1, Folder 4)
  - "Citizens Action Pamphlet", Citizens Defense Fund, ca. 1974 (Oversized 1, Folder 5)
  - Clearwater Sailing Posters, 1978; 1980 (Oversized 1, Folder 6)
  - Clearwater Navigator Mock-up, 1978 October (Oversized 1, Folder 7)
  - "Fighting for Our Future", Grand Council of the Cree, 1991 August 1 (Oversized 1, Folder 8)
  - "First Annual Blessing of the Fleet", Poster, 1990 (Oversized 1, Folder 9)
  - "The Grand Council of the Crees Wishes to Thank?", Newspaper Advertisement, 1992 (Oversized 1, Folder 10)
  - "Ground Water Availability in the Hudson River Basin", Undated; map, photocopy (Oversized 1, Folder 11)
  - Hudson Panorama Poster, Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 12)
  - "New York's Canals and Connecting Waterways", Map, New York State Department of Transportation, Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 13)
  - New York Environmental Images Calendar, 1981 (Oversized 1, Folder 14)
  - New York Statewide Comprehensive Recreation Plan, Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 15)
  - "No Thank You Hydro-Quebec -- There Are Alternatives", Northeast Alliance to Protect James Bay, Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 16)
  - North River Friends of Clearwater Display #1, Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 17)
  - North River Friends of Clearwater Display #2, Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 18)
  - North River Friends of Clearwater Display #3 [incomplete], Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 19)
  - North River Friends of Clearwater Display #4, Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 20)
  - North River Friends of Clearwater Display #5, Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 21)
  - North River Friends of Clearwater Display #6 [incomplete], Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 22)
  - North River Friends of Clearwater Display #7, Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 23)
  - North River Friends of Clearwater Display #8, Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 24)
  - North River Friends of Clearwater Display #9 [incomplete], Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 25)
  - North River Friends of Clearwater Display #10, Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 26)
  - North River Friends of Clearwater Display #11, Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 27)
  - North River Friends of Clearwater Display #13, Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 28)
  - North River Friends of Clearwater Display #14, Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 29)
  - North River Friends of Clearwater Display #15, Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 30)
  - "North River Friends of Clearwater", Poster, Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 31)
  - Northern Rights, Southern Lights: Connections to James Bay, ca. 1993 (Oversized 1, Folder 32)
  - Nuclear America Map, 1978 (Oversized 1, Folder 33)
  - "A Present from New York": Sloop Poster, Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 34)
  - "Rick Hind for Congress" Poster, Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 35)
  - Sloop Illustrations, [19]75 (Oversized 1, Folder 36)
  - Sojourner Truth Arrival Announcement, Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 37)
  - "The Status of Transportation in the Capital District", Capital District Transportation Committee, 1979 (Oversized 1, Folder 38)
  - "Stop James Bay II", Poster, Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 39)
  - "Water: Use It to Make Life More Fun", Poster, Environmental Protection Agency, Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 40)
  - "Wetlands, Wildlife, and You!", Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 41)
  - Newspapers (unfoldered), 8.43
    - New York State Environment, 1976 April-1978 June (Oversized 2)
      May & April 1977, April 1978 missing.
    - Parade: "Why We Must Save the Hudson", 1978 November 26 (Oversized 2)
    - Suburbia Today: "Irish Heritage of Dance" and "Hudson River Troubador", 1981 September 27 (Oversized 2)
    - Times Record: "Hudson River Celebration", 1977 September 22 (Oversized 2)
  - Availability of Ground Water in the Unconsolidated Aquifers of the Mid-Hudson River Basin, 1987 (Oversized folder 1)
  - City of Albany Map, Undated (Oversized folder 2)
  - Geologic Survey Maps (Oversized folder 3)
    Albany (1953), Capital District (undated), Delmar (1953).
  - Geologic Survey Maps (Oversized folder 4)
    East Greenbush (1953), Glens Falls (ca. 1960).
  - Geologic Survey Maps (Oversized folder 5)
    Hudson North (1953), Mechanicville (1954), Ravena (1953).
  - Geologic Survey Maps (Oversized folder 6)
    Troy North (1954), Troy South (1953), Utica (1964).
  - Geologic Survey Maps: Hudson River -- Saratoga County to Northern NY State, ca. 1950s (Oversized folder 7)
  - Great Hudson River Revival Posters, 1979-1983; 1987; 1990 (Oversized folder 8)
  - Hudson River: Coxsackie to Troy, Map, 1977 (Oversized folder 9)
  - Hydroelectric Development and Native Communities of Northern Quebec, Hydro-Quebec Map, 1991 (Oversized folder 10)
  - Hydrologic Unit Map, State of New York, 1974 (Oversized folder 11)
  - North River Friends of Clearwater Display #12, Undated (Oversized folder 12)
  - Potential Well Yield from Unconsolidated Deposits in the Lower Hudson and Delaware River Basins, Map, 1987 (Oversized folder 13)
  - "Reinhabit the Hudson Estuary", Undated (Oversized folder 14)
  - Sloop Silhouette "Albany" banner on canvas, Undated (Oversized folder 15)
  - 1. Land Suitable for Development: Coeymans to Albany, Map, Capital District Regional Planning Commission, 1976
  - 2. "Clearwater Pumpkin Festival" Painted Canvas Banner, Undated
  - 3. Clearwater Silhouette Poster, Undated
  - 4. Mock-ups for advertisement in Price Chopper Ad: Clearwater Sloop Festival, labeled August 8, Undated
  - 5. Department of Agriculture Smokey the Bear/Flower Poster, Undated